A Guide to the Papers of Robert Taylor and Virginia Hunter Lyne Tunstall, 1803-1972
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of Robert Baylor and Virginia Hunter Lyne Tunstall, 1803-1972
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
8606-g
There are ca. 265 items in this collection.
This collection contains items, ca. 1803(1868-1972), pertaining chiefly to Robert Baylor Tunstall and his wife, the former Virginia Hunter Lyne. There are also some papers relating to the Heiser and Tunstall families. Items include correspondence, papers, printed material, and bound volumes.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was bequeathed to the Library on May 25, 1988 as part of the Estate of Robert Baylor and Virginia Hunter (Lyne) Tunstall, in care of Roy Rector, Trust Officer of Sovran Bank, Norfolk, Virginia.
Scope and Content Information
Correspondence includes letters of Rosalie Heiser, Robert Baylor Tunstall's aunt on his mother's side, and from C. C. Coleman of England. Papers relating to the Chrysler Museum at Norfolk are concerned chiefly with the controversy surrounding the gift of the Chrysler Art Museum owned by Walter P. Chrysler, Jr., and the subsequent changing of its name from the Norfolk Museum of Arts and Sciences in April 1971. Virginia Hunter (Lyne) Tunstall was a member of the Board of Trustees of the Norfolk Museum of Arts and Scienes at this time. These papers include correspondence, copies of the resolution and deed of gift between the Chrysler Art Museum of Provincetown, Inc. and the Chrysler Museum at Norfolk, reports and other records, and printed material (especially newspaper clippings). Correspondents writing in answer to invitations from Robert Baylor Tunstall to Pewter Platter Club engagements include William E. Boroh, Samuel Bowles, George Harvey, Martin W. Littleton, Supreme Court Justice Horace H. Lurton, Morris Schaff, Moorfield Storey, Oscar W. Underwood, and Attorney General George W. Wickersham. Material compiled for Virginia Tunstall's trips to Europe and the Orient include notes, brochures and other printed material. In addition, there are notebooks and a photograph album relating to the University of Virginia.
Contents List
- Chrysler Museum at Norfolk
  - Chrysler Museum at Norfolk 1970-1972 (Box 1)
  - Chrysler Museum at Norfolk: Newspaper Clippings 1970-1972, n.d. (Box 1)
  - Chrysler Museum at Norfolk: Records 1970-1971 (Box 1)
- Correspondence of the Heiser and Tunstall families 1885-1973, n.d. (Box 1)
- Invitations to Law Association Dinners 1924 (Box 1)
- Memorial Plaque for Richard Baylor Tunstall (and Isabel Mercein Heiser Baylor) 1955-1956 (Box 1)
- Miscellany of Virginia Hunter (Lyne) Tunstall 1922-1924, n.d. (Box 1)
- Pewter Platter Club 1910-1912, n.d. (Box 1)
- Recipes n.d. (Box 1)
- Residence of Ashley Road, Shaker Heights, Ohio 1936 (Box 1)
- Trips 1961-1963
  - Trip to Europe 1963 (Box 1)
  - Trip to the Orient--Hong Kong 1961-1962 (Box 1)
  - Trip to the Orient--India 1961-1962 (Box 1)
  - Trips to the Orient--Japan 1961-1966, 3 folders (Box 2)
  - Trip to the Orient--Thailand 1961-1962 (Box 2)
- Writings of Robert Baylor Tunstall 1899, n.d. (Box 2)
- Writings of Virginia Hunter (Lyne) Tunstall and Others n.d. (Box 2)
- Commonplace Book of Virginia Hunter (Lyne) Tunstall 1924, n.d., Bound volume (Box 2)
- Law Class of 1902 of the University of Virginia; booklet sent to Robert Baylor Tunstall 1909, Bound volumes (Box 2)
- Lecture Notes for "Synopsis of the Law..." kept by Robert Law Tunstall 1868 (Box 3)
- Ledger of Grimball and Tunstall 1870-1888 (Box 3)
- Miscellaneous Poetry and Prose, and Articles re: the Tunstalls kept by Virginia Hunter (Lyne) Tunstall 1921-1967, n.d. (Box 3)
- Photographs of Virginia scenes ca. 1990 (Box 3)
- Poetry and Journals of Verse kept by Virginia Hunter (Lyne) Tunstall 1918-1928 (Box 4)
- Travel Log kept by Virginia Hunter (Lyne) Tunstall n.d. (Box 4)
- "Trivia or Things that Have Amused Me" kept by Virginia Hunter (Lyne) Tunstall 1919-1957, n.d., 2 folders (Box 4)
- Indenture between Abraham Lewis and Frederick Shonnard for land in New York, NY 1803 May 19
- United States Pasport Certificate for Robert Baylor Tunstall 1902 July 5
- Blueprint of "Planting Plan," by landscape architect A. Donald Gray for the Tunstall residence on Ashley Road, Shaker Heights, Ohio 1936 March 17